Control center, please respond.
控制中心请回答
Ghost No.1
幽灵1号
Moving towards the Sky Ladder.
正朝天梯方向移动
Received, please respond.
收到请回答
Abandon docking.
放弃对接
Calculate the target spacecraft's velocity.
测算目标飞船的速度
Dad.
爸爸
Alert.
警报
Detected damage to the main structure of Gravity Port 2 in High Orbit Ring 1.
检测到高空一环2号重力港主结构损毁
Alert, the gravity system in High Orbit Ring 1 is about to fail.
警报高空一环重力系统即将瘫痪
All personnel, prepare for weightlessness and impact prevention.
所有人员做好失重防冲撞准备
Alert, Well No. 4 in High Orbit Ring 3 has been punctured.
警报高空三环4号井被击穿
Alert, large-scale explosion in the truss.
警报桁架发生大规模爆炸
Alert, chain reaction of debris in spaceport.
警报太空港发生碎片连锁反应
Alert, major structural damage to the spacecraft dock.
警报 太空船坞出现重大结构性损坏
Alert, disintegration of the main structure of the space repair factory.
警报太空维修工厂主体结构解体
Alert, all personnel, stop working
警报所有人员停止作业
and go to the emergency assembly point.
前往紧急集合点
High altitude station hit by space debris.
高空站受太空碎片撞击
What's happening?
怎么回事儿啊
Chain reaction occurred.
发生强连锁反应
Stop moving.
停别搬了
Low altitude station's docking platform is forcibly locked.
低空站船坞平台强制锁定
What about that thing?
那货怎么办
Sky Ladder cargo compartment fully locked.
天梯运载舱全线锁定
This is the first time we have encountered this kind of situation.
头回碰上这事儿
All transportation and supply operations have been terminated.
运输补给作业全部终止
What's going on?
什么情况
Where did the debris come from?
哪来的碎片啊
Repeat, all personnel, stop working.
重复所有人员停止作业
Listen to the broadcast.
听广播
Isn't he at the high altitude station?
你那谁不是在高空站
Shall we go to the assembly point?
去集合点吗
Why do you have my badge?
我工牌怎么在你那
Take me to the control room.
带我去测控室
Hurry up.
赶紧
Sorry, the control room is inaccessible now.
不行测控室现在
Don't waste my time.
废什么话
The wallfacer is up there.
面壁者在上面
Quickly.
快
Ok.
好的
Follow me quickly.
快跟我走
This way.
这边
Alert, the fiber optic data transceiver has been hit.
警报光纤数据收发终端受到撞击
Alert, All personnel outside the cabin, take cover immediately.
警报所有舱外人员迅速避险
Stay away from the dense area of space debris.
远离太空碎片密集区
Central axis electrical shortage.
中轴电能短缺
Conventional lighting temporarily suspended.
常规照明暂停使用
Partial auxiliary functions temporarily shut down.
部分辅助功能暂停供电
Team One arrived at the 3D traffic hall.
一队抵达立体交通大厅
Received.
收到
Now only short-range wireless communication is available.
现在只有短距离可以无线通讯
Keep track of each other's positions in the space suit at all times.
时刻保持宇航服间的定位
Be careful not to fall behind.
大家注意别掉队
Understood.
明白
This cabin is the most severely damaged.
这里的舱道受损最严重
Be careful during repairs.
修补时注意安全
Understood.
明白
What's this?
这是什么
This is...
这是
The gravity system in High Orbit Ring 1 has been restored.
高空一环重力系统已恢复
F-ring and G-ring roadways.
F环道G环道
Cabin pressure is below the emergency limit.
舱压低于应急限值
All personnel, do not approach
所有人员请勿靠近
or forcibly open the airtight cabin door.
或强行开启气密舱门
Solar panel wing damaged.
太阳电池翼损毁
Battery pack malfunction.
蓄电池组故障
Power system has switched to emergency mode.
电源系统已切换至应急模式
Are you okay?
你没事吧
Here.
来
You're not wearing your helmet.
头盔都不戴
Fortunately, nothing happened.
幸好没事儿
Young people are always careless.
年轻人就是马马虎虎
Thank you.
多谢
I never expected to have such luck.
没想到我老苗还有这运气呢
Let's go quickly.
咱赶紧走
What is this?
这是
Where are we going?
去哪里啊
Let's go, Wallfacer.
走啊面壁者
Why are you standing there?
愣这儿干吗
I have never deceived anyone in my life.
我老苗这辈子没坑过人
Rest assured.
放心
Come on.
来
Are we not waiting for the rescue team?
不等救援队吗
When will they come if we wait?
那等到什么时候啊
We can't even send signals to the ground.
往地面的信号都发不出去
Come on.
来
Don't hit your head.
别碰头啊
Thank you, Master Miao.
谢谢你苗师傅
You're welcome.
不客气
The fiber optic cable going up is not broken.
就往上的光纤没坏
But there is only the Yellow River station with counterweights up there.
但上面只有配重的黄河站
How much force can you make
还当多大劲儿呢
with this small arm?
这小胳膊
Go back and exercise more.
回去多练练
It's good for your health.
对身体好
Chairman.
主席
All wired and wireless communications at the high-altitude station are down.
高空站有线无线通讯全断了
Only the pre-disconnection data is available.
只有失联前的回传数据
We are currently attempting remote observation.
我们正尝试远程观测
But what about the damage
但附近的卫星也
to the nearby satellites?
受损情况怎么样
The truss has exploded.
桁架发生爆炸
The bottom fiber optic cable has been damaged.
底部光缆被损坏
The resulting space debris is being tracked
产生的太空碎片正在追踪
some of it will burn up in the atmosphere.
部分会在大气层烧毁
No.
不
I mean the top of the space station.
我是说高空站顶部
Where was Luo Ji's location detected?
罗辑的定位在那出现过
Is this the location where the spaceship hit?
这个是飞船击中的位置吗
What about the images?
图像呢
Emergency satellites from other orbits have been redirected.
紧急调了其他轨道的卫星过去
The high-orbit light cone is changing trajectory
高轨的光锥号正在变轨
but it will take a long time.
但要很长时间
Okay.
好
We need to know the situation inside as soon as possible.
里面的情况得尽快知道
Is there a way to get up there?
有办法上去吗
We can launch from the low-orbit station
可以让低空站发射
they are closer.
他们离得近
Isn't Officer Shi right there?
史警官不是正好在那儿吗
That won't work.
不行
The low-orbit station has also lost contact
低空站也失联了
and the air disaster will trigger their safety lock.
而且空难会触发他们的安全锁定
The Aerospace Department can send three
飞船动不了
spacecraft to come closer
航天部可以近调三艘空天飞机
and directly enter.
直接进去
It's currently the fastest
目前最快的方式了
and only way.
也是唯一的
Chairman.
主席
That's impossible.
这不可能
What's wrong?
怎么了
Just now,
就是
the signal near the high-orbit station disappeared instantly.
高空站附近的信号瞬间消失了
Above.
上面
There seems to be an invisible shield.
像突然多了个透明的罩子
Wireless signals are all gone.
无线信号都没了
Shouldn't be..
不应该啊
The spacecraft cannot detect anything.
飞行器也监测不到
How could the electromagnetic environment
这么大范围的电磁环境
of such a large area be destroyed?
是怎么被破坏的
What's going on up there?
上面什么情况
Who are you?
你是谁
How did you get in?
怎么进
You stop.
你站住
Yang Gong.
杨工
They belong to the Ministry of Defense and Security of the Earth
人家是地球防务安全部的
I'm in charge of the safety of the Wallfacer.
负责面壁者的安危
Has the Yellow River Station also lost contact?
黄河站也失联了吗
No.
没有
But it's an unmanned nuclear power plant.
但那是没人的核电站啊
What the hell is going on?
这都什么玩意儿
You come.
你来
Did you make contact?
联系了吗
I sent an email,
邮件发了
but no one answered the call.
但通话没人接
Keep trying.
继续打
It's strange.
奇怪
Infrared observations hit the target.
切中红外观测
What is this?
这什么东西
I don't know.
不知道
Try using the imaging spectrometer.
用成像摄谱仪试试
Radio observations cannot penetrate the blind spot.
射电观测都没法穿透盲区
Reset the observation system.
重置观瞄系统
No, no, no.
不行不行不行
How can we see the high-orbit station clearly
这哪看得清高空站啊
from 16,000 kilometers away?
隔着一万六千公里
The observation system has already reached its limit.
观瞄系统已经到极致了
Did PDC give any instructions?
PDC有指示了吗
We've been trying to contact them,
一直尝试联系
but communication keeps breaking down.
但通讯总出问题
Yang Gong,
杨工
the signals of the top and bottom fibers are definitely cut off.
上下的光纤信号确定是断了
What's going on?
怎么回事
Let me check the communication module.
我去检查下通讯模块
Dr. Ding,
丁博士
to make a long story short,
我长话短说
No
不用了
don't worry about the ladder.
天梯你操心就行
I need to say something more serious.
我得说点更严重的
The satellite received full-band information before.
卫星之前收到了全波段信息
The maint point is that the ball lightning capture ship lost control
大概内容是球状闪电捕捉船失控
and deviated towards the direction of the ladder.
朝天梯方向偏航
Chairman,
主席
I request permission to publicly disclose the B436 project data on a small scale.
我申请小范围公开B436号项目资料
Granted.
允许
Thank you.
谢谢
I tried to speculate about what just happened on the ladder.
我尝试推测了下天梯刚发生的事
It should be directly related to the ball lightning.
应该和球状闪电有直接关系
So what I'm about to say
所以下面我要说的话
may go beyond everyone's understanding,
会超出所有人的认知
but I will try to explain it as clearly as possible.
但我会尽量说清楚
Ball lightning will choose a target to attack.
球状闪电会选择目标进行攻击
The specific frequency spectrum of the ball lightning
特定频谱的球闪
will only attack one type of target.
只会攻击一种目标
Can you tell me if
问一下
the main body of the ladder is still there?
天梯主体还在吗
Of course.
当然啊
Then the situation may be worse.
那情况可能更糟
What does that mean?
什么意思
Currently, the spectrum identified by the ball lightning
目前球闪已识别的频谱
has only two types.
只有两种
At the molecular level,
在分子层面
for targetting organic or inorganic substances respectively.
分别针对生物DNA和无机物
If the ladder still exists,
如果天梯还在
it suggests that this ball lightning
那说明这颗球闪
may be attacking human bodies.
很可能是攻击人体的
However, the report shows
可报告显示
that this ball lightning has just destroyed its target.
这颗球闪刚摧毁了标靶
Yes,
没错
but the spectrum has definitely been rewritten.
但频谱肯定被改写过
Although I don't know how it was done,
虽然我不知道是怎么操作的
at that time,
那个时候
the survivors on the ladder
天梯上的幸存者
should have been its target.
应该才是它的目标
What will happen to them?
他们到底会怎么样
Professor Wang,
汪教授
you should have guessed it.
你应该猜到了
Humans will resonate with the ball lightning
人类会和球闪发生共振
and be quantized by it.
被它量子化
The data she left
她留下的资料里
only wrote this,
只写了这些
but the fact must be more complicated.
但事实肯定更复杂
Will the quantized people disappear?
那些量子化的人会消失吗
I cannot answer
这个问题
this question directly.
我没法直接回答你
Our world likely exists in a macro-universe,
我们的世界很可能存在着一个宏宇宙
so
所以
macro-matter will be randomly distributed in space.
空间中会随机分布着宏物质
I previously participated in capturing macro-nuclei in North China.
我之前在华北就参与过宏原子核的捕捉
Now, what was born on the ladder
现在天梯上所诞生的
should be a macro-electron.
应该是一颗宏电子
When it reacts with the human body,
和人体反应的瞬间
it spontaneously forms a complete macro-system
跟某个宏原子核相结合
combined with a certain macro-nucleus.
自发形成的一个完整的宏系统
For now I call it a quantum body.
我暂时叫它量子体
But,
不对吧
if a new system is really generated,
要真产生了一个新系统
why didn't it happen in Mr. Taylor's ground experiment last time?
那上一次泰勒先生的地面实验为什么没有
As you said,
就像你说的
the ground will not have it.
地面不会有
The high-altitude station is located in space
高空站位于太空
and is exposed to an extremely low-temperature environment after being damaged.
破损后就暴露在极低温的环境里
Under this premise,
这个前提下
the thermal motion of particles will be suppressed to a minimum
粒子的热运动会被压到最低
and can only move in a limited space
只能在有限的空间里运动
to combine with each other.
相互结合
Only then can there be
才有可能会是束缚态
a bound state and a system.
才有系统可言
But regardless of which quantum state,
但不论哪种量子态
it cannot exist stably
在宏观维度也根本
in the macro-dimension.
没法稳定存在
Unfortunately,
对吗
this world is
可惜这个世界
not as simple as in the books.
没书里那么简单
Countless sophons are watching us,
无数智子在看着我们
and regardless of whether the observer effect is strong or weak,
无论观察者效应是强是弱
they will maintain the stability of this quantum body,
都会维持这个量子体的稳定性
allowing it to retain its quantum properties
让它既保留量子性质
while continuously posing a threat to us.
又可以对我们造成持续威胁
that for us
那对我们来说
What does this threat mean for us?
这个威胁意味着什么
You can understand
您可以理解为
it as the ball lightning breaking the boundary between macro and micro.
球状闪电击穿了宏观和微观的界限
The quantum body
它所形成的量子体
it forms is like a fungus
像一朵霉菌
infecting our macro world.
感染了我们所在的宏观世界
Once it starts to expand,
一旦它开始扩张
the entire space will produce changes that
整个空间都会产生我们不了解
we do not understand and cannot control.
更没办法控制的异变
So, are you saying
所以你是说
that the real disaster has just begun?
真正的灾难才刚开始
Is that right?
对吗
I can only say,
我只能说
I hope we still have time.
但愿我们还有时间
The inspection of redundant items
多余物检查已完成
has been completed,
刚检查了
and the terminal is restarting.
终端在重启
Please return to the cabin and conduct radiation testing as soon as possible.
请舱外作业返回人员尽快进行放射性检测
We will soon be able to communicate with the ground.
很快能和地面通信
Look,Yang Gong,
老杨看
there is an aircraft near the high-altitude station.
高空站附近有飞行器
Has the PDC started the rescue mission?
PDC开始救援了吗
But the satellite signal has not been restored.
但卫星信号都没恢复
How can we wait for the rescue mission?
救人这事儿怎么能等呢
Once the platform is unlocked, we will hurry up and go up.
平台一解锁咱也赶紧上去
Chairman,
主席
the rescue spacecraft has arrived.
救援飞船到了
Connect immediately.
马上连线
Understood.
收到
What's wrong?
怎么了
It seems that the spacecraft's altitude is a bit off.
飞船姿态好像有点儿问题
No. 2 navigation system is malfunctioning
2号导航系统失灵
and cannot avoid obstacles.
无法避障
It is switching to manual operation.
正在切换手动操作
This is the measurement and control.
这里是测控
Observe the surrounding environment
观察周围环境
and pay attention to collision risks.
注意碰撞风险
The first power distribution system has failed.
1号配电故障
The propulsion system is malfunctioning.
推进系统失灵
Beware of debris,
注意碎片
take emergency evasive action.
紧急规避
It's too late.
快来不及了
Low altitude station communication has been restored
低空站通信已恢复
Sky Ladder Flight Control Center
天梯飞控中心
This is Yang Jinbiao.
这里是杨锦标
Communication just resumed.
通讯刚刚恢复
We captured the air crash.
我们拍到了空难
Chairman.
主席
What should we do now?
现在怎么办
Stand by for now.
先待命吧
I may have found some clues.
可能找到了点线索
Chairman.
主席
I'll leave first.
我先下了
I believe
我觉得
Where there is a will, there is a way.
天无绝人之路
Everything will be fine
没事的
So,
那
how do we get back to the ground?
咱们怎么回地面啊
We'll go back the way we came
怎么来就怎么回去啊
The downward fiber is broken.
朝下的光纤坏了
But the nanofilament is fine.
但纳米丝没事儿
Otherwise,
不然
The sky ladder would have collapsed long ago.
天梯早垮了
Don't worry.
放心
The alarm didn't mention any damage to the transport module.
警报里没说运载舱受损
Don't expect any rescue.
等救援是别指望了
Take the vehicle down the central axis.
顺着中轴乘车
I'll take you down.
我带你们下去
If you see the PDC Chairman later,
回头见了 PDC主席
Remember to mention me.
记得跟她提一嘴啊
This is my work ID
这我工号
Remember it.
记得啊
Okay.
行啊
If you want something, just ask
想要什么直接说
I haven't thought about it yet.
没想好
Let's talk about it later.
再说吧
Miss,
姑娘
Could you please look around for the supply pack?
麻烦您周围找找物资包
We'll need it on the way.
咱路上用
Okay.
好
No.
不
I'll go
我去
She'll stay here.
她留在这儿
You have to help me pull this thing.
您得配合我拉这玩意儿
You need to be strong enough.
力气够大才行
I know where it is.
我知道在哪儿
I'll be back soon.
很快回来
Continue to calculate the escape pod's landing point in real-time.
继续实时计算逃逸舱的落点
All follow-up rescue operations are canceled.
上去的后续救援全部撤回
What does that mean?
什么意思
Chairman.
主席
Aren't we going to rescue them?
不救了吗
Conventional rescue efforts are ineffective.
常规救援不起作用
There's no need to risk more lives.
没必要让更多人冒险
Is Ding Yi ready yet?
丁仪还没好吗
No news yet.
还没有消息
Chairman.
主席
He's here.
他来了
Over here.
我这边
Ding Yi.
丁仪
If you have a solution, let us know.
有什么解决办法尽管说
All the resources here are available.
这的资源都能调用
There's no solution yet.
办法还没有
But there's a clue about this wireless communication blind spot.
但这个无线通信盲区有点眉目了
Give me a split screen.
给我个分屏
Received.
收到
Hydrogen atom electronic orbit diagram.
氢原子电子轨道图
Are you sure?
你搞错了吧
Yes.
不
this one
就这个
Use it as an analogy to this newly formed quantum entity.
用它来类比这个新诞生的量子体
I speculated earlier that
之前我推测
when the ball lightning spaceship lost control,
球闪飞船失控以后
at the moment of interaction with the human body,
和人体产生反应的瞬间
a stable macro nucleus
跟一个稳定的宏原子核
formed this new system.
形成了这个新系统
It sounds a bit complicated,
听着是有点复杂
but this structure is actually
但这个结构其实在理论上
similar to the hydrogen atom diagram in high school textbooks.
和中学课本上的氢原子图差不多
How do we verify it?
怎么验证呢
Hasn't particle experimentation been suspended?
粒子实验不是中止了吗
There's no way to verify it,
没法验证
but it's probably correct.
但大概率是对的
Because it's the only way
因为只有这样
that makes sense.
才说得通
We can do it now.
可以拉了
What?
什么
Master Miao.
苗师傅
What did you say?
你说什么
I said
我说
The winch and guide rail are both okay.
曳引机和导轨都没问题
We can go up now.
咱们能上去了
Are you ready to engage the brakes?
你准备拉闸
Okay.
好
Should we engage it now?
现在拉吗
Master Miao.
苗师傅
Doctor.
博士
Now is not the time to take chances.
现在不是碰运气的时候
Of course,
当然
But the word "probability"
但概率这个词
is the biggest difference between the quantum world and ours.
就是量子世界和我们的最大差别
There,
在那里
all possibilities exist
一切可能性都是存在的
and they exist simultaneously.
而且是同时
Like the hydrogen atom, a quantum body is in a bound state.
量子体和氢原子一样是束缚态
We can divide it into several layers of energy zones
我们可以按照概率密度
based on the probability density,
也就是对人的危险程度
which corresponds to the level of danger to humans.
把它分成好几层的能量区
The deeper it goes, the more dangerous it becomes.
越往里越危险
The spacecraft we just saw
刚才的飞船应该就是
accidentally touched the outermost layer of the quantum body.
无意间接触到了量子体的最外层
The outer layer
外层
is where the rescue ship lost control.
就是救援飞船失控的位置
Yes,
是的
from here on,
从这里开始
the chaotic magnetic field forms a shield
紊乱磁场形成了屏蔽网
that not only blocks wireless signals
不仅隔绝了无线信号
but also damages electronic equipment,
还会损坏电子设备
cutting off all communication with those inside.
让我们和内部的人完全失联
Is anyone
如果
still alive?
有人还活着的话
You are asking
你是想问
whether they will "die"
会不会“死”
right?
对吗
First, tell me,
先告诉我
what do you think "death" is?
你觉得死是什么
Breathing stops,
呼吸停止
no heartbeat,
没有心跳
that's what you call death,
那你说的死
but in the quantum world, it's nothing.
在量子世界根本不算什么
In the micro dimension,
在微观维度里
It can only be said that all the particles that make up a person
只能说构成一个人的所有粒子
exist with infinite probability
它们存在的概率
spread out
被无限平摊
and diffused
扩散
until you are completely broken down
直到宏观维度里的你
into elementary particles in the macro dimension.
彻底被打散成基本粒子
Therefore, when facing a quantum body,
所以人在面对量子体的时候
destruction
毁灭
should happen unconsciously,
应该是在不知不觉中发生的
but from a scientific perspective,
但从科学的角度讲
the word "destruction"
毁灭这个词
is not accurate,
并不准确
because nothing is
因为没有什么
really destroyed.
真的毁灭了
Momentum and angular momentum remain,
物质动量还在
Angular momentum is still
角动量还在
just like a deck of cards
就像一副扑克牌
still has 54 cards,
还是54张
just shuffled.
只是重新洗牌了而已
But life
但生命
is like a royal flush.
就是一手同花顺
Once shuffled,
这么一洗
it's all..
什么都没了
Gone.
没了
Are you talking about the people inside?
你是说上面的人吗
You just said that this quantum body has many energy zones
你刚说这个量子体有很多能量区
with varying levels of danger.
危险程度不一样
Yes,
对
the outermost shielding layer
最外面的屏蔽层
is the wireless communication blind spot you mentioned.
就是你们说的无线通信盲区
It doesn't harm humans much,
对人的伤害并不大
but it covers the entire space station,
但覆盖了整个高空站
preventing us from rescuing them.
让我们没法儿进去救援
The innermost layer is the core zone
最里面是核心区
with the highest probability density
概率密度最高
and is most deadly to any survivors.
对幸存者来说也最致命
Is this just your guess?
这些是你的猜想吗
It's a clue left by a friend.
一个朋友留下的线索
I can understand her metaphor.
她的隐喻我大概能懂
We worked together on Project B436,
我们在B436项目共事过
so
所以
in this area,
人类在这个区域里
What the hell.
见鬼了
humans are doomed more thoroughly than in the usual sense of death.
比普通意义上的死亡更彻底
I call the middle layer
量子体的中间层
of the quantum body the consciousness layer.
我叫它意识层
With a lower probability density,
概率密度没有那么高
if anyone is still alive,
如果还有人活着
they might be there.
可能就是在这儿了
Do people inside the quantum body
那量子体里的人
see visible probability clouds?
是不是会看到肉眼可见的概率云
Probability clouds should not be visible,
概率云按理说不会被看到
as observation causes the cloud to collapse.
因为观察会引起云的坍缩
But this time,
但这次
the observer is inside it
观察者在它内部
perhaps an exception.
或许是个例外
In here,
在这里面
so-called spacetime
所谓的时空
will vanish like foam.
会像泡沫一样稍纵即逝
If survivors cannot collapse the probability
如果幸存者没法通过观察
cloud through observation,
让概率云坍缩
their macro existence
那他自己的宏观存在
will decay infinitely,
就会无限衰减
a process
这个过程
as natural as ice melting into water.
会像冰融化到水里一样自然
My eyes.
我的眼睛
What's wrong with my eyes?
我的眼睛怎么了
No,
不行
I can't die here.
我不能死在这儿
Zhuang Yan is still waiting for me.
庄颜还在等我
But what worries me more
我更担心的是
is the high-speed movement of the macro-electron
宏电子的高速运动
which will cause a very strong gravitational disturbance.
会造成非常强烈的引力扰动
In this way,
这样的话
the vicinity of the quantum body
量子体附近
is like spreading out
就相当于铺开了一张
a gravity network that almost only locks the human body spectrum.
几乎只锁定人体频谱的引力网
Even if the survivors can temporarily hide in a safe area,
哪怕幸存者能暂时躲在安全区域
they cannot avoid the influence of gravity.
也没法避开引力的影响
What?
什么
Once the macrogravitons start to fluctuate,
一旦宏引力子开始涨落
ultimately, everyone inside of it
最终上面的所有人
will be captured by the quantum body.
都会被量子体捕获
What's going on?
怎么回事
What kind of place is this?
什么鬼地方
Its existence is
它本身的存在
not targeting a specific person,
不是针对某一个人
but because of the corresponding spectrum,
而是因为频谱对应
you are within its range.
你又在它的范围内
It is difficult not to be affected by the entire energy level.
很难不受整个能量层级的影响
How come only I am upside down?
怎么只有我倒过来了
No,
不对
this is not normal gravity.
这不是正常重力
In this process,
而在这个过程里
people will slowly devolve into a superposition state like Schrödinger's cat,
人会像薛定猾那只既生又死的猫一样
which is both alive and dead.
慢慢演化为叠加态
If many of me are superimposed together,
如果很多个我叠加在一起
I will see objects in multiple spaces at the same time.
就会同时看到多个空间里的物体
No way.
不会吧
If one of me is a mirror image,
如果其中一个我是镜像的
then what I see and leave behind
那我看到和留下的痕迹
will also be a mirror image.
也会是镜像的
What happens
发生什么
is entirely determined by probability.
完全由概率决定
What the hell?
什么鬼
This is impossible.
这不可能
This is unreasonable.
这不合理
This is a space that breaks the rules of classical physics,
这是个打破了经典物理规则的空间
but it's not that this spacetime has changed,
但不是这个时空发生了变化
rather
而是
that many parallel spacetimes overlap or unfold at a certain position.
很多平行时空在某个位置重叠或者展开
Is it a space problem?
是不是空间的问题
If I use astronomical observation methods,
如果用天文观测方法的话
assuming that the celestial body is at 0 degrees,
假定天体是0度
using right ascension plus hour angle,
用赤经加时角
I want to see...
我要看看
It seems to be the hour angle coordinates.
真是时角坐标
It seems that below is the horizon circle,
看来下面就是地平圈
and it is perpendicular to gravity.
而且垂直于引力
Above is the zenith.
上方就是天顶
I just need to find the extension point of the plumb line.
我只要找到铅垂线的延伸点
3 star hours,
3恒星时
45 degrees hour angle,
45度时角
then the right ascension position,
那赤经位置
the observation angle is equal to...
观察角等于
Is it wrong?
不对吗
Or did I miss something?
还是我漏了什么
Light refraction,
光线折射
gravity source,
引力源
correcting altitude,
修正高度
or maybe my assumed position is wrong.
还是我假定的位置不对
Anyway,
不管了
It's all over.
完蛋了
None of the angles are normal.
没有一个角度是正常的
It's okay.
没事
I need to stay calm.
我要冷静
There must be a way.
总有办法的
I still need to take Zhuang Yan away.
我还得带庄颜离开
Take a deep breath.
深呼吸
There must be a solution
一定有出路的
as long as I find the pattern.
只要找到规律
I can't die here.
我不能死在这里
But you said that Zhi Zi's monitoring makes the quantum body,
但你说智子监视让量子体
at least part of it, in a stable state.
至少是它的部分处于稳定状态
Can humans also survive in the same way?
那人类是不是也能用同样的方式活下来
You mentioned the observer effect.
你说观察者效应
Yes,
没错
theoretically,
理论上可以
it's possible.
我只能说
All probabilities exist there.
如果在那儿一切概率都存在
Everything is possible.
一切可能都是可能
Perhaps there is a one-in-ten-million chance
那或许会有千万分之一的机会
of a miracle happening.
是奇迹发生
What happened?
发生什么了
What's wrong with your eyes?
你眼睛怎么了
It's okay
没事
Let's go.
走
Do you not want these things?
东西不要了吗
I've been looking for them for so long.
我找了好久的
What about Master Miao?
苗师傅呢
Don't look back.
别回头
Hurry up.
快走
What exactly happened?
到底发生了什么
Where it Master Miao?
是不是苗师傅他
What will happen to this quantum body in the end
这个量子体最后会怎么样
if it cannot be stopped from spreading?
如果没能阻止它扩散的话
Our world
我们所在的世界
is like a still three-dimensional lake.
只是个静止的三维湖面而已
Quantum entities are like throwing a stone on the water's surface,
量子体像是在水面丢了一颗石子
The more particles it absorbs,
它吸收的粒子越多
The larger the phase space of the quantum state it needs to maintain,
需要维持的量子态的相空间就越大
Eventually,
最后
The calmness of the entire lake will be broken.
整个湖面的平静都会被打破
No matter how deep the lake is,
不论天梯的纵深多远
It doesn't matter.
都没有区别
Anyway, sooner or later,
反正迟早
it will be occupied by the waves of the quantum state.
都会被量子态的波浪占据
The fire alarm of the shelter has been lifted.
避难所火灾警报已解除
What's going on?
怎么回事
Please be careful when entering, staff.
请工作人员小心进入
Where's the master?
师傅人呢
Report the problem as soon as possible.
尽快报修
You closed the door.
你关门
How will he come in?
他怎么进来啊
The high-altitude station's first and second rings are severely damaged.
高空站1环道2环道受损严重
Is it because the elevator shaft was not repaired?
是电梯井没修好吗
Or...
还是
We need to split up.
我们要分头走
We have been isolated from the rest of the rings.
已与其余环道隔离
Even if I can't help,
就算我帮不了忙
At least tell me,
至少可以告诉我
let me know what's going on.
让我知道怎么回事啊
All the cabin sections here are locked now.
现在这里的舱段全都锁死了
Let me help you.
我帮你吧
No need.
不用
There are only two of us left now.
现在就剩咱俩了
We have to hurry,
得赶紧走
Turn on the inner cabin signal.
除入内舱内服信号
No other survivors have been detected.
未检测到其他生还者
Please be careful
请注意安全
and use the escape equipment properly.
规范使用逃生设备
Luo Ji,
罗辑
Don't be like this.
你别这样
Okay.
好了
Remember this red button?
这个红色按钮记得啊
It's used when launching.
发射时用的
Just press it.
按下它就行了
There's a little bit of purified water here,
这有点纯净水
but not much.
但是不多
It should be enough for you to wait for rescue.
应该够你等待救援的时候用
What about you?
你怎么办
There's only one here.
这只有一个
When it's ten kilometers away from the ground, the parachute will open automatically.
距离地面十公里的时候会开降落伞
And then no matter where it lands,
那之后无论在哪里着陆
it will automatically send a beacon.
都会自动发送信标
The PDC can receive it.
PDC都能收至ij
If you encounter danger after landing..
万一降落后遇到危险
No.
不行
If anyone has to go, it should be you.
要走也是你走
Your safety is the most important.
你的安全最
My safety is none of your business.
我的安全关你什么事
What do you know about the current situation?
知道现在什么状况吗
And what about Lao Miao?
那老苗
I can't tell if he's dead or alive.
我都说不清他到底算不算死了
You kept saying you wanted to leave earlier.
刚才不是你一直说要走吗
Now that I'm asking you to leave, you won't go.
我现在让你走你又不走
What else do you want?
你还想怎么样
Are you not satisfied?
你还有什么不满意
I'm not dissatisfied.
我没有不满意啊
I'm grateful.
我很感激
You should know.
你搞清楚
I'm asking you as Wallfacer.
我是以面壁者的身份要求你
I'm commanding you.
我在命令你
Go as far as you can.
有多远就滚多远
Staying here is meaningless.
赖在这没有任何意义
PDC has to listen to me.
PDC都得听我的
Why won't you listen?
凭什么你不听
Right?
对吧
Remember.
记着
When pressing this button,
除了按这个按钮
just press it once.
按一下就行
Don't touch anything else.
别的都别碰
The helmet?
头盔吗
There.
那儿
The life support system here
这里的生命循环系统
can protect you until you land safely.
完全可以保护你直到安全着陆地面
You don't have to...
你不用
Escape pod launch successful.
逃逸舱启动成功
I pressed it.
我按了
I'm listening to you.
听你的
If this is my last view
如果这是最后的景色了
It's not bad,
倒也不错
Right?
对吗
You're good, Da Shi.
可以啊大史
You really had me fooled.
还真被你给蒙着了
I've been wanting to ask...
我一直想问